Wow!
すーごーい　ペンギンって　泳ぐの上手だね
Penguins are such good swimmers!
Yeah, they're all goofy on land, though!
うん　陸ではちょっと間が抜けてるのにね
The penguins must be pissed to hear that from you!
晶馬に言われちゃ　ペンギンもイラとするな
What's that supposed to mean?
何だよ　それ
Sorry, I got a phone call.
悪い　ちょっと　俺電話
A girl again?
また　女のか
Slow down!
程々にね
大丈夫だよ　上手くやってるから
Don't worry, I'll stick with this one!
Ugh, I don't want to be infected by yucky playboy Kanba-germs!
アー　嫌だ嫌だ
女にルーズなバッチ冠葉菌が移っちゃ
Hey, Sho...
ね　晶ちゃん
Mom!
ママ　見て　ペンギン
Look, penguins!
こら　大声出さない
Don't yell.
ペンギンは飛んで逃げたりしないよ
It's not like penguins can fly away.
だって
But...
Recyclable
Flammable
Inflammable
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
くるくる回る
君の瞳探して回る
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
駅のホーム
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
響くファンファーレ
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
ごめんね
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
運命が笑う
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
臨界点突破してんだ
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
限界なら既に去って
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
絶対的支配だって
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
崩壊
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
叫ぶよ
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
僕は目を閉じるよ
本字幕由诸神字幕组(www.kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
时间轴：wcaster  压制：wcaster
日听 xHunter 翻译：英英 校对：凌可乐
That will be 1,284 yen.
千二百八十四円でございます
Yay! Penguin!
やった　ペンギン
What color ribbon would you like?
リボンは何色になさいますか
Let's see... Pink, please.
えーと　じゃ　ピンクで
Okay.
かしこまりました　少々お待ちください
Please wait one moment.
It's the one I saw earlier.
あの子　さっきの
Wait!
待って
Hey, little penguin.
ねえ　ペンギンさん
B
Open
Close
B
嫌だ　驚いた
Sheesh, you gave me a scare.
何処へ　行くの
Where are we... going?
Wealth without Work
Pleasure without Conscience
Knowledge without Character
Commerce without Morality
Science without Humanity
Worship without Sacrifice
Politics without Principle
ここ　いつもの図書館だ
It's the library I always go to.
返却お願いします
I'd like to return these books.
Sputnik Weirdo
Learn to Earn Ten
Times More
Christine
Stephen Queen
はい　ご返却ですね
Sure, returning the books.
あの　カエル君東京を救うって本は何処にありますか
Um, where can I find the book Super Frog Saves Tokyo?
Returns
Return Date March 20th (Mon.)
Today October 15 (Sat.)
少々お待ちください
One moment please.
そのタイトルの登録はありませんね
That book doesn't appear to be in our database.
前に見た事があるんです　ここで
I've seen it before.
きっとあるはずなんですけど
I'm sure it's here.
似たタイトルと間違われたとか
You may have mistaken it for a similar title.
何か他に心当たりの検索項目はありますか
Would you like to search for it by another term?
少し自分で探してみます
I'll try to look for it by myself.
前に探した記憶を辿れば　多分
I should be able to find it by tracing my memory.
カエル君東京を救う
Super Frog Saves Tokyo.
確か　この辺に
I think it was somewhere around here...
ペンギンさんも探してくれる
Will you help me search for it, little penguin?
ア　待って
Wait!
ねえ　何処行くの
Hey, where are you going?
あれ　こんな所に　ドア
Huh? Was there always a door here?
"Ka" line
Super Frog Saves Prof. Azuma
Super Frog Saves Dr. Yanagibara
痺れるだろう
Isn't it mesmerizing?
いらっしゃい　どんな本をお探しかな
Welcome.
What kind of book are you looking for?
あ　えっと
Uh, um...
ようこそ　中央図書館空の穴分室へ
Welcome to the Central Library's Hole in the Sky Annex.
空の穴
Hole in the Sky?
私こちらで司書を務めております眞悧と申します
I am Sanetoshi, the head librarian here.
How may I be of service to you?
どうぞなんなりとご用命を
Um, then... Could you help me find the book Super Frog Saves Tokyo?
あの　じゃ　カエル君東京を救うって本を探してもらえますか
As you wish.
かしこまりました
Now that you have come, I promise to find the book you desire
こちらへいらっしゃった方には
必ずやお客様が深くお心に抱いた御望みの一冊
in this repository of knowledge and sea of recollection.
この膨大な知識と記憶の海より探し出していただける事でしょう
Like finding a single pearl in all the seven seas.
宛ら七つの大海からたった一つにも　真珠を見つけ出すように
この眞悧誠心誠意お手伝いいたします
I, Sanetoshi, am at your service.
変な人
What a strange man.
これじゃない
This is not it.
Not this one either.
これも　違う
Um, is this really an annex of the Central Library?
あの　ここで本当に中央図書館の分室なんですか
なんだか　やけに広いような気が
It feels unusually spacious.
分室ですよ　図書館の
It is the library's annex.
Sanetoshi
とは言え　久々のお客様です
However, you are our first guest in a long time.
This is not a place just anyone can enter.
ここは誰もが入れる場所ではないんですよ
Only chosen guests are allowed inside...
選ばれたお客様のみが立ち入る事を許される
A special library.
特別な図書館
Does that mean I'm special?
じゃ　私は特別なの
Yes, you're very special person chosen by fate.
ねえ　　運命によって選ばれた特別な
Found it.
有った
Super Frog Saves H-Trio
See? This is the Story of You, which you have been seeking.
ほら　これがお探しの貴方の物語だ
Three years ago, she had two friends.
三年前　その女の子には二人の友達がいたんだ
Precious companions who shared the same dream.
将来の夢を分かち合う大切な仲間
The three girls made each other shine like stars bound by gravity.
三人の女の子達はまるで引力で引かれ合う星々のように
互いが互いを照らし
Himari - Elementary School - Classroom -- Inside - *Friendship after school. The three started it all. Preparing for the audition.
Kicking off soon
The 7th Idol Audition
This one might work!
あ　これいいかも
Yeah! Let's use this one for our application.
うん　じゃ申し込みの写真はこれで決まりね
I filled out most of it yesterday.
昨日大体書いておいたんだ
All we have to do is print out this picture and glue it on!
後はこの写真をプリンターとして貼るだけ
Oh! That's our Hikari!
おお　さすが光莉ちゃん
Are you sure it's all filled out? You didn't forget anything?
大丈夫　書き漏らしとかない
You're the one to talk!
7th
Auditi
Narita South, Suginami Ward, Tokyo
雲雀ちゃんがそれ言うか
Attach Picture Here
Trust me!
任せて
Guardian's Consent
Guardian's Name
Takakura Kenzan
But...
だけど　今年はどうする
Group Name
What should we use this year?
I know! The Otters!
はい　ラッコズ
No! That sounds like a comedy troupe.
駄目だよ　それじゃお笑い芸人みたいじゃ
We got rejected because of that last year!
Audition Application Form / FAIL / Processed
去年はそれで惨敗したでしょう
You sure?
えー　そうかな
How about The Penguins?
じゃ　じゃペンギンズは　なんかさ　フランスの女の子っぽくない
Doesn't that sound like a group of French girls?
That sounds more like a Little League baseball team.
むしろ少年野球のチームだって
But penguins are cute!
でも　可愛いじゃ　ペンギン
"H."
エッチ
ええ
How about Triple-H?
トリプルエッチってどうかな
Triple-H?
トリプルエッチ
Yes.
そう
"H" is the first letter in Hibari, Hikari, and Himari.
雲雀
光莉
ひまりの頭文字のエッチ
And there's three of us, so Triple-H!
それで三人だから
トリプルエッチ
That's awesome!
あ　すめっちゃいい
Yeah, that's not bad!
うん　悪くないよね
Group Name
Triple-H
Nice, nice!
いちゃん　いちゃん　なんだか今年は行ける気がする
I'm starting to think we have a chance this year!
We're taking the video for the audition tomorrow, so don't forget to bring the matching ribbons.
明日は応募用のビデオ撮りだから
お揃いのリボン絶対に忘れないでね
Or we won't make the deadline!
締め切りに間に合わなくなっちゃう
Yes, Ma'am!
ホイ　ホイ　もう購入済みであります
I already bought it!
Don't forget, Himari.
ひまりちゃんも忘れないでね
Yes, of course.
うん　勿論
Right. Something like that happened.
そう　そんな事もあっだっけ
But this is not the book that you seek.
でも　君が探しているのはこの本じゃない
Let us move on to the next book, then.
なら　次の本を探そうか
After all, there are many, many more books here.
何しろ　ここにはまだまだこんなに本があるのだから
Well then, this is the next story.
さて　お次の物語はこれだ
Super Frog Saves Takakura Himari
That night, the girl obtained the matching ribbons she had been pestering her mother about.
その夜
女の子は予てように母親に願っていた　お揃いのリボンを手に入れたんだ
However...
けれど
Himari - Takakura Home - Living - Inside (Night) - *It was the wrong ribbon. I couldn't forgive her for that. But, who would've thought...
There you go.
はい　出来た
Look how pretty you are!
ほら　とても美人さんよ
You're all ready for the audition!
これならきっとオーディションもばっちり
No!
違う
These don't match... at all!
こんなのお揃いじゃない　全然違う
Sorry...
御免なさい　ひまりの言っていたのは売り切れてで
The kind you wanted was sold out.
But this one is a similar color and I think lighter tone suits you better-
ほら　でもこれだってよく似た色だし
少し淡色の方が　お母さんひまりにはよく似合うと
I don't want this one!
こんなの要らない
It's meaningless unless it's the same as Hibari and Hikari's!
光莉ちゃんと雲雀ちゃんとお揃いじゃなきゃ　意味がないもん
I'm sorry.
御免ね　じゃ　お母さん明日隣町に行って　同じのを買って来てあげるから
I'll go next town and buy you the same one tomorrow.
It can't be tomorrow! It'll be too late!
明日じゃ駄目なの　間に合わない
I promised them that you'll buy matching ribbons...
約束したのに　お皆とお揃いのリボンちゃんと買ってくれるって
You're a liar, Mom.
御母さんの嘘つき
Himari...
ひまり
Go buy it now. You promised!
今買って来て　約束したじゃない
Keep your promise!
約束を守ってよ
Watch out!
危ない
Are you bleeding?
血が
Mom!
御母さん
Call the ambulance!
きゅう　救急車を
Himari - Hospital - Hospital Room - *Mother in bandages. Himari in regret. I'm sorry, Mom. What have I done?
Her cuts were more deeper than we thought and there was a lot of bleeding,
思ったより傷が深く出血も多かったので
暫く入院して　安静になさってください
so we're going to admit her for a few days.
We did our best, but the wound on her face will probably scar...
ベストは尽くしましたが
お顔の傷は残ってしまうかと
Mom...
御母　さん
Himari. Let me see your face.
ひまり　顔上げなさい
You're not hurt?
怪我　してないのね
うん
Yes.
I'm so relieved!
ああ　よかった
もしひまりが顔に怪我でもしてたら
If something had happened to your face, I would've never forgiven myself.
御母さん　一生自分が許せないところだった
嫌だ　もう　そんな顔しないの
Geez, don't look so sad!
It's not a big deal.
大した事ないから
You'll become an idol, right?
ひまりはアイドルになるだものね
I'm really looking forward to it.
御母さんもとても楽しみなの
So, I'm so happy you weren't hurt.
だからひまりに怪我がなくて　本当に良かった
I'm sorry, Mom!
御免なさい　御母さん
御免なさい
I'm sorry...
今のはなかなか上出来
That was quite touching.
The story of love between a mother and a daughter.
母と娘の愛情物語
It's a tearjerker, don't you agree?
結構泣けるんじゃないのかな
Oh? Not this one either?
これでもないと
My, my, we have quite a demanding guest here today.
やれやれ　今日のお客様は手強いな　さすがに
As to be expected.
We have no choice.
仕方ないですね
Let's head farther... deeper down.
では　もっと奥へ
もっと深い所へ参りましょうか
Next day, the girl told her friends everything that had happened–
次の日　女の子は二人に全てを打ち明けたんだ
That her selfishness had scarred her mother for life.
自分のわがままで　母親に一生治らない傷を負わせた事
That she couldn't get her hands on the ribbon, as promised.
約束のリボンを手に入れられなかった事
Perhaps the girl wanted to punish herself by telling them the truth.
女の子は正直に話す事で　自分に罰を与えたかったのかもしれないね
But those two might hate her for that.
でも　そんな自分を二人は嫌いに成ってしまうかもしれない
Those thoughts made her throat tighten up...
そう思うと　声も掠れて
Himari - Elementary School - Near Shoe Shelves -- After School - *Friendship by the pond. The forbidden play. Barefoot Gon chapter. What will happen...
I'm so sorry.
本当に御免ね
That's why I don't have the ribbons today.
だから　今日はリボン持って来られなかったの
You two go ahead and make the video yourselves.
だから　ビデオは二人で撮って　それから　オーディションも
The audition, too.
What?
ええ
I don't have the promised ribbon.
私誓いのリボンないから
I wonder how we can help your mom get better.
ひまりちゃんのお母さんどうしたら　早く元気に成ってくれるかな
ええ
Your mom's in the hospital, right?
だって　お母さん　入院しちゃってるんでしょう
Let's do something we can do for her.
何か私達に出来る事しようよ
What? Yeah...
うん　でもビデオが今日撮らないと締め切りが
But the video...
You have to record it today, or the deadline...
Who cares?
そんなの　どうでもいいじゃ
Our best friend's mom is hurt.
親友のお母さんが怪我したんだもん
We're worried about her too.
私達だって　心配だよ
Hmm... But what can we do?
でも私達に出来る事って
I know!
History
World History
Japan - Manga
World - Manga
Religion - Myth
Shintoism
Buddhism
Christianity
そうだ　図書館で借りた裸足のゴンに書いて有ったよ
I read it in Barefoot Gon from the library!
Unpatriotic Son
Froggy Son
Heart is Ash White
Kindness and Anger
Upcoming Upheaval
Tearful Enlister
Evacuated Child
Kamikaze Squad
Koi's Fresh Blood
My Final Destination
Mark of P
Roomless Bard
Burning Blood Surge
Ship of Reward
Sight of Hell
Absence of Rice
Second Horror
The sick mom drank fresh Koi blood to get better!
病気にお母さんに鯉の生血を飲ませて　精をつけるって
That's it!
それを　鯉なら学校の中庭にいるわ
There's a Koi in the courtyard!
いたよ　そっち　そっち
It's going your way!
It went your way, Himari!
ひまりちゃん　そっち行ったよ
Sweet! We cornered it!
ほらほらほら　追い詰めた
静かに　焦らないで
Gently, be patient.
Yes!
やった
Go for it.
早く遣っちゃって
End its life in one shot!
ガッズンと一発うみまして
息の根を止めるのよ
止めを刺して　新鮮な鯉の生血を
Finish it off and obtain the fresh Koi blood!
Right.
うん
Hey! What are you doing?
ほら　お前ら何してる
Staff Room
What exactly were you up to?
一体どういうことだ
That Koi was a gift from last year's graduates.
あの鯉は去年の卒業生の贈物なんだぞ
You have nothing to say for yourselves?
答えられないのか
You leave me no choice.
なら　仕方ない
I'll have to call your parents.
家族の人に事情を話すしかないな
I-I...
私が
It's my fault.
私のせいです
I dragged them into it because I really wanted to drink Koi's fresh blood.
わたしが鯉の生血をどうしても飲みたくて二人を無理やり誘ったんです
違います　私が二人を誘ったんです
No. I was the one who asked them to do it.
私どうしても百歳まで生きたくて　長生きしたくて
I wanted to live to a hundred... I wanted to live a long life!
No! I wanted to surprise my parents by living to a hundred!
違う
私が百歳まで生きてパパとママを驚かすようとしたの
Hibari... Hikari...
雲雀ちゃん　光莉ちゃん
本当は　私の御母さんが
The truth is... My mother–
違う
No!
違うよ
That's not it!
だって
But...
私なんです　だから電話するなら私の家だけにしてください
It was me.
So, only call my parents if you have to.
違う　違う　私が二人を誘ったの
No, no! I was the one who asked them to do it.
だから電話うちだけにして
So just call my parents!
Wh-What's going on here?
何だよ　こりゃ
Hibari... Hikari...
雲雀ちゃん　光莉ちゃん
うん
ありがとう
Thank you.
何言っての　私達はトリプルエッチじゃん
Why did you say that for? We're Triple-H.
そうよう　三人で運命共同体でしょう
Yeah, our fates are bound as one, right?
うん　二人共大好きだよ
Yes.
I love both of you.
どうやら　これも御気に召さないらしいね
It seems you are not very pleased about this either.
そう　本当に君が読みたかったのはこの続き
Right, the part you really wanted to read was the rest of this book.
Himari - Elementary School -- Field - Himari Going Home - *End of friendship. Last day of school. Something hit my bag.
覚えてる　あれは私が最後に学校へ行った日
I still remember it.
That was the last day I went to school.
二人に逢ったのもあれが最後だった
It was the last I saw of the two of them.
そして　二年後　君はまたあの二人と再会する
And two years later, you encountered them again.
思ってもみない残酷な形で
In an unimaginably cruel fashion.
Today's
Slogan
Out-of-the-park Home Run
Don't Give Up on your Dreams
Dream Hit
もしあんな事がなかったら
If that had never happened, you would be with them.
君も彼達と一緒に
Maybe you would be singing with them as Triple-H.
そう　トリプルエッチとして　歌っていたかもしれないね
そうかもしれない
Maybe.
でももう過ぎた事だもの
But it's in the past.
ほう　では何故君はこの物語を探していたのかな
Oh? Why then, were you searching for this story?
いじましい自己憐憫に浸るため
To drown yourself in petty self-pity?
No. I just wanted to make sure it's in the past.
違う
もう終わったのだという事を確認したかっただけ
Really?
本当
Perhaps deep down, you despise them.
実は彼女達を恨んでいたりして
I don't despise them.
恨んでなんかいない
Because they were my true friends at the time.
だって　あの時二人は私の本当の友達だったから
I still cheer them on from the bottom of my heart.
今だって　心から二人を応援してる
You're an admirable girl.
君は素敵な女の子だね
But then again, why did that happen to such a kind-hearted girl?
でも　それなら
どうして　そんな心ばえのいい女の子があんな事になってしまったんだろうね
I don't know.
分からない
Didn't you come here to search for the answer?
君はそれを探しに来たんじゃなかったのかい
No... I don't know...
いいえ　分からない
I just don't know.
分からないわ
You say it's in the past,
君は終わっきり事だと言うけど
Super Frog Saves TVideo
but has the story really ended?
本当にもう物語は終わってしまったのだろうか
As I said, the book you truly want to read from the very bottom of your heart is here.
言っただろう
ここには君が心の奥深くで真実読みたいと欲する御望みの一冊がある
まだ物語が終わったわけじゃない
The story has yet to end.
そう　例えば
Yes, for example...
Broken
This.
こんなものとか
それは何
What is that?
This is the wedding veil bestowed upon the bride of fate.
これは運命の花嫁に捧げる花冠
Bride? Me?
花嫁　私が
Whose bride will I become?
誰の花嫁になるの
The answer to that question is probably at the destination of fate.
多分　その答えは運命のいたる場所にある
The destination of fate?
運命のいたる場所　それは何処
Where is that?
You should already know that place.
君はその場所を知っているはずだけど
I'll tell you the answer when you need me again,
after you return to your world.
答えは　君が元の世界に戻って
僕を必要とした時に教えてあげよ
About the destination of fate, whose bride you are...
運命は何処へ至るのか　君は誰の花嫁なのか
Until then–
それまでは
No.
駄目
My feelings can't reach you
届かない思い
Too bad.
残念
Our bonds being torn apart
引き裂がれて絆
The clouds drift away regardlessly on a
何もなかったように
雲は流れていくさ
Gray Wednesday
灰色の水曜日
Don't forget this.
こいつを忘れちゃだめだよ
サア　思い出して
Now, remember the spectacular past
輝いていた頃を
When everything was bright, when you fell in love
何もかも眩しくて
恋に落ちてた頃を
サア　思い出して
Now, remember the time we loved each other
Child Broiler
愛し合ってた頃を
Let's share the fruit of fate.
運命の果実を一緒に食べよ
When we stared into each other's eyes
真剣な眼差しで
Thank you for choosing me.
選んでくれてありがとう
見つめ合って頃を
Right, I had someone very precious to me.
そうだ　私にはとても大切な人がいた
Now, remember the spectacular past
サア　思い出して
He's my soulmate.
彼が私の運命の人だ
輝いていた頃を
夢に生きてた頃を
When you lived for a dream
When you loved each other
Survival Strategy!
生存戦略
愛し合ってた頃を
Huh? Did I fall asleep?
あれ　寝ちゃってた
Was I dreaming about something?
なんだか　夢を見てたような
I don't remember anything, though.
全然覚えてないけど
Hello, this is Takakura...
はい　高倉
ええ　晶ちゃんが事故
What? Sho was in an accident?
車にはねられたって
He was hit by a car?
What do you mean, Ringo?
リンゴちゃん　どいうこと
Super Frog Saves Tokyo
Frozen World
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
全てが欲しい
繋がれたいたら
僕らはどうして
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
もがくのだろう
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
それは君じゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
君のせいじゃない
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
だからそうじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
夢のままじゃない
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
上手く伝えきれないけど
Dear my future
Dear your future
Dear you future
I finally remembered our connection.
ああ　ようやく思い出した　俺とお前との繋がりを
Let's settle this once and for all.
いいだろう　決着をつけようじゃないか
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy: Live to a hundred.
生存戦略　百まで生きる